# **Kelsey Flynn**

Web Developer with strong organizational, analytical, design and communication ability with international experience that commits to continuous learning. Experience in education & HR/compliance creates a strong grasp of liaising with both businesses and users of all backgrounds, regarding deliverables.

Calgary, AB, T2V E34 (403) 808-2573 kelseyflynnn@gmail.com

**GitHub:** /KSFlynn007 **LinkedIn:** /kelseysflynn

### **WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS**

## **Code Club** — Full-Stack Developer

February 2021 - March 2021

- Architected an event meet-up PWA built with React; used Google Calendar API and Amazon AWS Lambda serverless platform to fetch events.
- Developed with TDD techniques, FP & OOP paradigms, and data visualization.

## myFlix DB — Full-Stack Developer

December 2020 - January 2021

- Designed REST API with MongoDB Atlas, for a future online movie database application. Constructed endpoints in server-side code for all CRUD requests.
- Established security processes including password hashing encryption, JWT authentication and CORS.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **CareerFoundry**, Remote — Full-Stack Web Development Certificate

November 2020 - April 2021 (Expected)

Created various projects as a full-stack developer; handled all stages from
planning to final deployment, and through this developed capability in HTML,
CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React and React Native.

# **SheCodes,** Remote — Introduction to Coding Certificate

September 2020 - October 2020

• Created functional app mockups through studying the fundamentals of web development.

# **University of Calgary**, Calgary, AB — Bachelor of Arts

September 2012 - April 2016

Linguistics Major, Management and Society (Business) Minor

- Studied data collection and optimization to further extrapolating patterns and rulesets.
- Developed interpersonal, creative and presentational skills; organized and delegated sections of projects to individuals based on abilities to create cohesive teams.

#### **PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES**

HTML

CSS/SCSS

JavaScript

Libraries/Frameworks: jQuery, React/Redux, React Native, Angular, Bootstrap,

Foundation

Paradigms: Functional

Programming, Object-Oriented Programming

#### **DEVELOPER TOOLS**

Programs: GitHub/Git Version Control, Postman, Jest, pgAdmin 4, Robo 3T, MongoDB Atlas, Visual Studio

Databases: PostgreSQL,

MongoDB

Platforms: Firebase

Cloud Platform: Amazon AWS

**Hosting:** Github Pages, Heroku, Netlify

**OS:** Windows/Powershell, Linux/Ubuntu

**Chrome Tools:** DevTools, Lighthouse, Redux DevTools

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Franworks**, Calgary, AB & Remote — HR & Compliance Administrator

April 2019 - November 2020

- Demonstrated ability to coordinate with different companies, learn new systems without guidance, utilize data analysis to improve processes and update with kanban management.
- Enabled best practices of keeping documentation through experience with overseeing collection, editing and auditing of databases and legal documents.
- Developed leadership skills in projects by handling all licensing and Worker's Compensation accounts in North America; coordinating with governmental agencies, remote representatives.
- Extended multi-tasking ability between workloads through continuing to hold Office Manager position concurrently.

## **Franworks**, Calgary, AB & Remote — Receptionist/Office Manager

March 2018 - April 2019

• Demonstrated ability to handle multiple department's needs, represent a brand to external clients, and take leadership roles for neglected projects.

## **Private Tutor** — *Paris, France*

September 2017 - December 2017

• Demonstrated ability to take on project contracts and complete work within a tight deadline.

# **The Reading Foundation,** Calgary, AB — Clinician

May 2015 - April 2017

- Demonstrated ability to work in a large team to tailor programs to individual files, strategizing cooperatively on cases, and making continuous improvements to projects without advanced notice.
- Extended empathy for end users by implementing cultural competency and behavior management skills with ESL students and students with learning disabilities.

#### **SKILLS**

Written & Verbal Communication

**Problem Solving** 

Analytical thinker

Organized & Methodical

Time Management

Team Leadership & Project Management

MS Office, G-Suite applications, Survey Monkey, Formstack, Basecamp & Monday.com